Surya N

Power Bi Developer

Power BI Expert with 4 years of rich experience in creating compelling reports and dashboard using advanced DAX. Looking to work with an esteemed organization that gives me an opportunity to utilize my existing analytical skills and help make better business decisions.

suryaandroidl@gmail.com

99665 90837

in linkedin.com/in/suryaandroidl

github.com/suryaandroidl

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quality Specialist

Amazon Development center Hyderabad

06/2019 - Present

Achievements/Tasks

- Responsible for getting, understanding the business specs, preparing technical Specs.
- Designed Power BI data visualization by utilizing cross tabs, maps, scatter plots, pie, bar and density charts.
- Used Power BI, Power Pivot to perform the data analysis on different data sources and used Power View and Power map to visualise reports.
- Published Power BI reports in Power BI service and made Power BI dashboards available for end users. Getting data from different data sources.
- Using different transformations like excel source, data conversions, lookup, OLEDB command, derived columns, OLEDB destination, etc.
- Loading these data into data warehouse like SQL server.
- By using these data warehouse, based on client requirement we generate the multilingual reports in SSRS.

NETWORK OPS SPECIALIST

Amazon Development Centre India, Hyderabad

09/2017 - 03/2018

Achievements/Tasks

- Perform data analysis and create PBI report using daunt chart and provide it drill down mechanism.
- Perform Power BI design and developed reports in Power BI
- Experience in Power BI, SSAS, using DAX Queries
- Seek advice and escalate issues when faced with tasks/problems outside the scope of the work.
- Installed, Configured Enterprise Gateway and Personal Gateway in Power BI Services.
- Published Power BI Reports in the required origination and made Power BI Dashboards

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Free Lancer

Faculty of Power Bi and Excel

04/2018 - 05/2019

Hyderabad

Tasks/Achievements

- Worked as faculty for Excel and Power BI at i-Zen Technologies.
- Trained more than 60 students in Excel and Power Bi.
- Participated and gave support to few Power BI projects.

SKILLS

Power BI Power Ouerv Power View DAX Outlook Microsoft Excel **SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS)** Powerapps Power Automate **Problem Solving** Documentation Agile Methodology RedShift

EDUCATION

Masters of Business Administration (MBA) St. Mary's group of institution

08/2014 - 10/2017

JNTU Hyderabad

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Resume in Power Bi

Created resume in power Bi and published it.

Covid-19 Dashboard

- Created an interactive Covid 19 dashboard.
- Dashboard updates on daily basis from online resource.

Tableau to Power BI migration

- Supported few Tableau to Power BI migration projects.
- Did few migration projects on my own.

SKILLS AND ABLITIES

Strong communication, problem-solving, and planning skills.

Smart working, Quick learner, Flexible and ability to work in a team.

Positive Attitude and enthusiastic in Teamwork. Adaptability, knowledge and focus on work.

CERTIFICATES

MS Excel # Jedi Certification.

Power Bi Certification.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Member of Fun Team at Amazon.

LMAQ Fun Team.

Organized and Conducted Live and Virtual Rewards and Recognition events at Amazon.